Independence and Education
独立和教育
Young Nirmala was also seized with Nationalist zeal
年轻的涅玛拉也受民族主义热情支配
She was always extremely energetic
她总是极其精力旺盛
And was a natural leader among her peers
是同龄人中自发公认的领袖
In 1942 during the Quit India movement
在1942年‘退出印度’运动期间
She participated in many daring episode of picketing
她参加与了许多英勇的游行示威
and was also part of an underground group that carried out many secret missions
同时也是执行秘密任务的地下组织成员
Because we were all college students
因为我们全是大学生
We all wanted to stop the colleges
我们都想停止学业
Then somehow or other we got into another kind of mysterious acting
然后我们设法参与了另一种秘密活动
to distribute bulletins, used to call them bullets
发传单 我们叫它们子弹
And spread disorder among students
在学生中产生骚乱
That time students were very alert
那时侯学生们非常警醒
that we should have our independence
我们应该有自主权
We should be a free country
我们应该生活在一个自由的国家
and people were not so dishonest as they are now
那时候人们不像现在这样不诚实
After that I joined science college
之后，我加入科学院
Because I wanted to do medicine
因为我想去学医学
But science college we had a strike
但在科学院我组织了罢课
And I became the leader of students
我成了学生领袖
So they asked me to get out of the college
所以他们让我离开学校
So I had to leave the college
所以我不得不离开学校
Then I went to Lucknow to study
接着我去了勒克瑙学习
in Ludhiana Women college that's also another missionary
在卢迪亚纳女子学院 也是一个教会学校
But from there I did my science
但在那里我修习了我的科学课程
And then I did My Medicine from Lahore
后来我在拉合尔学习医学